Charles Skiles Papers
Charles Skiles Papers
1940-1967
Skiles, Charles.
4.75 linear ft.
Over 2,000 original drawings for the panel cartoon Josephine, original magazine cartoons, correspondence, and clippings of published cartoons, including work for Dr. Pepper.
148668
Biographical History
Charles Skiles (1911-1969) was an American cartoonist.
Charles Skiles was born in Pekin, Indiana on December 29, 1911. Skiles drew the syndicated single panel cartoon Josephine for the General Features Corporation. Skiles also contributed cartoons published in magazines such as the Saturday Evening Post, Collier’s, McCalls, Good Housekeeping, Ladies Home Journal, Christian Science Monitor and the Wall Street Journal.
Skiles lived in Florida for most of his life and he died Feb. 14, 1969 at Halifax Hospital in Daytona Beach, Florida.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Charles Skiles Papers are arranged in three series: correspondence, original cartoons, and published material.
Correspondence (1946-1957), contains one folder of incoming correspondence regarding the use of Skiles' cartoons.
Cartoons (1940-1967) consists of original artwork and is divided into two subseries. Included in the collection are approximately 2,134 pieces of artwork for the Josephine panel cartoon. 1,626 items are dated, 483 cartoons bear only years and 25 items are completely undated. Items measure 7" x 9 3/4" and were drawn in ink on paper. Captions appear in blue pencil. The other subseries is magazine cartoons. These items have similar dimensions to the Josephine work and were produced in ink and watercolor on paper. Stamps are located on the back with Skiles' name and address as well as publication information.
The Published material series (1940-1965) contains clippings of Skiles' cartoons including his early work for publications such as Liquor News, foreign language versions of his cartoons and cartoons published for Dr. Pepper in 1943 along with a Dr. Pepper proof book.
Arrangement of the Collection
Josephine cartoons are arranged in chronological order. Magazine artwork is arranged alphabetically by publication name. Correspondence and published material is arranged as received.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Skiles, Charles -- Archives.; Dr. Pepper Co.; General Features Corp.; Josephine (cartoon); American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Advertising -- Soft drinks.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Children -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Comic books, strips, etc.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Charles Skiles, 1967.
Inventory
- Cartoons
  - Josephine, Click here for a detailed inventory.; 2,134 items
    - 1959-1961 Jun (Oversize 1)
    - 1961 Jul-1962 (Oversize 2)
    - 1963 Apr-1964 Feb (Box 1)
    - 1964 Mar-1965 Mar (Box 2)
    - 1965 Apr-Aug, 1965 Nov-1966 Oct (Box 3)
    - 1966 Nov-1967 Oct, undated (Box 4)
  - Magazine
    - The American Magazine, 1952-1955; 4 items (Box 4)
    - American Weekly, 1957; 1 item (Box 4)
    - Blue Book Magazine, 1952-1953; 6 items (Box 4)
    - Collier's, 1952; undated; 2 items (Box 4)
    - Farm Journal, 1957; 1 item (Box 4)
    - Look, 1954-1956; 4 items (Box 4)
    - National Enquirer, 1965; 1 item (Box 4)
    - Nation's Business, 1943-1953; 21 items (Box 5)
    - TV Guide, 1957-1965; 4 items (Box 5)
    - W.O.W., 1964; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Wall Street Journal, undated; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Unidentifiable, 1962-1966; undated; 41 items (Box 5)
    - Series C, 1952-1954; 11 items (Box 5)
    - Series F, 1966; undated; 37 items (Box 5)
    - Unscheduled, 1946-1947; 3 items (Box 5)
- Correspondence
  - 1946-1967, 1 folder (Box 1)
- Published material, clippings
  - Dr. Pepper cartoons, 1943 Aug; undated; clippings and Dr. Pepper proof book (Oversize 1)
  - Early work, circa 1940; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Foreign language, 1955-1963; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Foreign language, 1955-1963 (Box 6)
  - Illustrations, 1941-1955 (Box 6)
  - Published cartoons, 1946-1965 (Box 6)
  - Published cartoons, undated; 3 folders (Box 6)